try again uh we are doing a home lab now
and I'm just going to go ahead and say
what I did before I already I already
said this that I was muted so I'm going
to repeat it really quick so this video
at the beginning of the video is going
to be talking as with every video that
I'm going to post that's a I think going
to post as many live streams as I can
now to YouTube uh in raw form and I will
always put some sort of commentary at
the beginning and I'll always put some
sort of commentary at the end uh I did
make a mistake and just said you cannot
be me I actually made the mistake of
immediately starting to talk at the
beginning of the video of the live
stream before anybody could validate
that I was actually here and you know
they can hear me and I was
muted so by the time they finally came
in you know on both live streams they'll
have like this big 10-minute thing at
the beginning that says hey wait around
here I come and I don't want to do that
because I just want to push export on
Twitch because I'm lazy and I want it to
just go straight up to YouTube so I
start talking right away and and what
that means is a lot of you're going to
actually end up missing uh introdu some
of the preliminary introductory stuff at
the at the beginning but that is stuff
that I think will become apparent to the
people that stay around in live stream
for the whole thing so uh so this is
something new that I've been doing now
that I'm doing a lot more live streams
from the laptop and but today's topic is
the home lab and we're going to spend
two hours going through this I'm going
to talk through the whole thing today
rather than have you know the the muted
middle section with music um because I I
have to do a lot of things here I
actually have to do so this is a very
much a participatory thing there's a lot
of live chat going on we were just
congratulating somebody for passing
their security plus it was really
awesome um so it was this is just really
exciting and so the question about
setting up your own home lab and I I've
got it on the screen here I've got the
the the what we're going to do today um
this will be I don't know if it's going
to be the first I already have a
playlist called H lab on YouTube and
it's kind of messy uh there's a lot of
stuff in there I probably just going to
go ahead and add this anyway because I'm
not a fan of deleting videos off YouTube
sometimes people find even the old bad
stuff uh okay to look at so I am going
to go ahead and tell the story behind
what's prompting this um yeah you're
going to invest in a home lab yes let's
talk about that um and that's actually
why I'm doing this so I really hope that
all the people that are thinking about
building a home p uh a home lab make it
in here and they see this video and you
know they come in they leave comments in
YouTube which I never read but maybe you
come in the Discord maybe you can uh
come in the twitch you know with us live
um this is going to be a regular thing
um I don't know I'm just show you the
calendar really quickly so this is my
calendar including my personal calendar
and home lab section is uh afternoons on
Fridays uh my place of employment gives
me Friday afternoon uh is uh to do
educational things and so I've dedicated
that time to building and fixing and
updating my home lab including uh and
you'll notice we're streaming to the
software in development category today
instead of the Science and Tech category
I mean I don't even want to talk about
the historic drama I've made jokes about
the difference between those two and
been totally cancelled by certain
individuals in twitch uh just for making
the jokes um you know that's long
history the point of it is the reason
that I'm going to stream this to
software in game devb is because the
homeand that I am building is
specifically to fulfill my role as a
senior backend developer and so that is
my official title these days since they
brought me on full time uh when I was
actually when I was hired as a
consultant uh my official title was
Senior High Performance Machine learning
infrastructure engineer I know that's
kind of a mouthful um but you have to
know that it's not a f so you just have
to know that in order to know that's why
I am building the lab I am building and
those of you who are building labs for
other purposes and like het Tannis for
example is much more an operations and I
I am definitely in operations but just
more on the development side of things
um there's kind of a spectrum you know
even within operations you can have
people that are you know more developer
Centric even within operations they
write more of the scripts and and then
you have people that are more de opsy
that are Al that for that channel comes
to mind you know those guys are you know
doing a lot of cloud stuff and they're
doing a lot of uh a lot of terraform a
lot of anible a lot of cicd and all that
and and then you have like you know like
really core infrastructure operations
people that are like dealing with
Hardware all time so even within
operations there's this whole you know
spectrum and frankly even even within
backend development there's a whole
Spectrum so hopefully uh you know we you
can kind of get a handle on that that is
a topic that we we we flush out a lot
more in the beginner boost that I've
been doing every year for years uh we're
going to start up by way that officially
there's a plug for the beginner on
November 3rd uh November 3rd will be the
first beginner boost uh it's it's not
going to be sequentially what we're
going to do is we're going to pick up
the beginner views from 2024 that we
stopped earlier when I went on my trip
and everything so stay tuned for that
that'll be November 3rd if you want to
be here in the studio audience while I
record videos that are going to then go
up on skill. okay so so that is what's
going on with the
schedule um the home lab time so if you
just want to bookmark this time if
you're on YouTube the first time you're
hearing of it uh as of this moment you
know every Friday afternoon from 1:30 to
3:45 eastern time is going to be me
working on my home lab I got a late
start today and let me tell you why so
this is actually kind of an interesting
story um uh and I I I would actually I
don't know what should we do for story
time like how could I like make it more
fun for
you I don't know what to say I just
gonna so I'm just going to jump in
there's I wonder if I could like zoom in
or something like we like we need an
effect we need an effect okay here we go
Story
Time get your copy this is this is a
story okay this is a very short story so
don't worry I don't I am a very
longwinded person yes I know okay oh my
God I'm so big in the window I must be
pretty scary some people are very scared
right now okay here comes my story I'll
push you back far away I'll push you
back far away okay thr time with Rob so
I put that thing on the calter that I
just talked to you about right
laptop has self-esteem
issues oh no you saw my pajama pants I'm
totally
outed oh damn
okay once upon a time I bought a big ass
computer I bought a a huip packer HP
z640 actually I recently made team no
pants I actually recently made a video
about this and I might have to put an
amendment to that video because I have a
feeling I might not be sticking with
that recommendation you know why I got
to go buy another
one I know spoiler alerts okay so today
my you saw my schedule how I was late
for for for this thing today right so so
I went to to go turn on my some of you
know I'm in a middle of a move right
well we're still moving this is the new
apartment you're seeing little pieces of
here and there and
um I mean I was actually going to do
this stream from the back room my yoga
computer room and and the computer's
broke computer's broke yeah it's
actually pretty funny I I kind of wish I
had video of it trying to turn on so I
went it's just like $1,400 used
refurbishing machine it's it's a
kick-ass deal hey Ray and and so I went
to go turn it on I I found the power
plug I was so proud of myself you know I
found it it it it's a total mess in and
I was like oh my God okay then I plugged
the ethernet in and I I re retooled the
internet and everything got it all
worked up I was like oh great I'm I'm
all ready to like chop this up you know
today this just happened today yeah so I
was like I'm all ready to go chop up
this this this computer this into a
whole bunch of virtual machines and show
them off in my home lab you know no no
no luck no luck I I have the worst luck
in the world by the way I just feel like
I do so so what happened so I ended up
going to turn it on and it like started
screaming at me I mean literally it was
like was like five of these really loud
like annoying
things and I was like this this will not
do this cannot be and I was like oh [__]
what's going on I mean I thought did I
did I did I plug my UPS in somehow
because it was screaming at me like my
UPS was was yelling at me right
so so and then I looked on the front and
there's a red light where the power
button is and it's like blinking on you
know and then I was like hm and
eventually it died and I was like okay
maybe it'll go off or maybe I turned it
on wrong or maybe it got the power cut
you know and I just need to turn the
power back on again so so I I turned it
off I turned it off I held the thing
down you know you hold any button down
long enough and the thing will go off
whether you whether it wants to or not
and so I did I totally killed it and I
turned the thing off
and um yeah clean clean your fans I know
clean your fans you guys want to go
clean your fans so um and I mean okay so
it gets better because then I tried it
again so I plugged it in again and and
you know and I uh it did the thing again
and give it a yeah yeah I can't repeat
that just going on YouTube Mark see I'm
see that's the kind of comment that is
that was very funny but that's the kind
of comment that's not going to go on
YouTube if you want to see the not
suitable for work comments from Mark you
got to come on Twitch to see those okay
because I can't repeat them all right so
awesome hey awesome um and so this is
what happened so I ended up
getting uh totally screwed over and and
I let the thing run right so so I let it
go I let it I let it I let it stay on
right to be completely honest I forgot
about it so so I turned it on and it
stop beeping at me and I was like
thinking I was thinking to myself I had
my headlamp on where's my headlamp yeah
I was like this this I I'll reenact it
for you okay I'll reenact it for
you yeah I was like
H because it's really dark in there it's
I was like wow that does some very
interesting things to my anyway so that
has green did you know that yeah if you
push it enough it has like green and
stuff yeah oo
see yeah you thought you thought you
were going to learn things instead of
just learning how I'm playing with my
camo headband that lasts forever it'll
last through the zombie apocalypse
anyway how you doing
quiet Hawk Hawk to that thing okay
anyway so so I forgot about it I forgot
about it and then then then guess can
you guess what happened I'll let you
guess
okay I'm going to let you guess what
happened what came next okay so one the
thing is plugged in two it already
screamed at me and had the red lights
and then it stopped screaming but it was
still plugged in and I wasn't paying
attention to
it three I waited I waited I waited like
10 minutes right five minutes something
like that and all of a sudden I mean I
was like and I got up actually I got up
and I was walking around I like and then
I went out of the room and I was like
what the hell is that
noise yeah so I went
back I went back into the room I went
back into the room and the thing was GNA
explode it sounded like it was about to
explode it was like on maximum fan and
the fan was like and I was like oh my
God there's a short in the
motherboard and I just like totally now
the power the power supply is going to
melt and the whole thing and the
computer's like trying to save itself
and it was like it was like I mean and
this is an enterprise system and so if
you know the difference between
Enterprise and you your normal desktop
playing you know PC this is an
Enterprise System when when they get hot
those fans kick on man I mean I had
there was like fans after on top of fans
on top of fans and I could not hear
myself practically in there I was like
so my little yoga room with like the
Pretty Lights and everything go watch
the yoga video you can see those you
know it was it became it became like
this this place where it was about to
explode it was like now an it it was
like the loudest possible it noise you
could ever get in a rais floor area in
like a you know like a a hosting service
so so yeah my computer's
dead you know and I paid like I so I
opened it up again I actually obviously
I unplugged it right I took the thing
off and I opened it up again I've got my
headlamp I'm poking around looking in
there and I noticed there like a full
brand new web under one of the
areas and I was like was the spider like
chewing on the motherboard or something
because the spider's not there anymore
and it's not that big a cobweb there
wasn't that much of dust in there or
anything so I mean it's a motherboard
right and the only thing I can figure is
that um it was the the machine itself
while I was on my trip and I'm telling
you all of these things so you don't
destroy your own Hardware like I did and
honestly I thought I mean this is a
pretty robust system if you've seen it's
h HP z640 refurbished and you know I I
think it was I thought it was going to
be a lot more uh robust right so uh I
mean if this if this was actually at
work I would have never taken the
chances I'm about to tell you that I
took with this thing because seriously
people don't judge me Don't Judge Me
based on my Folly during managing my own
hob lab okay I already I already said
the whole thing um you have to go back
and watch the video so people were
asking what I did so this is what I
think happened so I'm GNA I Set This
Server tower on its side which is
totally fine to do that it's actually
designed to go you know to go in and out
of of a of a rack that way and I
actually I even have the the extra $300
Hardware kit to make it go in and out
which didn't work with my rack that I've
already donated to a community college
and um so anyway this this the computer
I think it was I laid it it was on the
carpet next to my desktop PC and the
only thing I can figure is that either
some moisture got in there on the board
um that area had we actually a year ago
some of you might remember uh the P
pipes bursting and two floors above us
in the apartment that I was in and we
got flooded on Christmas Eve and that
almost destroyed $20,000 worth of
computer hardware that I since donated
to some other place that that didn't
never got hit with the water thank God
uh but the you have to know that part of
the story because now I don't have any
hardware so the takeaway from this
is I gave away including two brand new
switches that I paid you know with VLAN
capacity and uh power over ethernet and
everything um so I'm a hardware less
yeah the only working Hardware I have
you know what I kind of like this
dilemma though because this this dilemma
that I find myself in right now
is forcing me to talk about you know my
wife tells me all the time don't give
your [__] away but when it comes to
Hardware particularly Hardware that
could be used by other people or you
know um I I think I don't think you
should wait right like for example I I
when I'm going through this move I have
so much Hardware I have like a a fully
functional Garin GPS that I stopped
using and didn't donate or give to
anybody and then the rubber like rotted
on it had I given it to somebody they
could have got some usage out of it
before doing it right uh buy Hardware
get Give It Away buy more Hardware
right it's all just baggage
right so my so we have a we have a we
have a decision to make all right so the
decision here
is do I buy more
Hardware or do I look at the
Alternatives and again this is the
reason I'm talking to you about this
particular dilemma this part of the
dilemma and the part the reason I like
it is because I am just like you I'm
just if you're just starting out and
you're a technologist and you maybe
found me for the beginner boost content
or something like that and you're asking
yourself what do I need to get good I
actually made a meme about this I'm
gonna go find it right now it's on my uh
I think I didn't think I think I posted
it to
Instagram yeah I posted I posted a meme
about this uh that's on my Instagram
yeah here we go not very many likes on
it right now but can you see
that so right here you have if you know
the Olympics the Olympics meme right you
got this Turkish guy who just pulls his
gun out and gets like second
place and so you know this is a home lab
and this is like multiple expensive
certifications and you know paying all
this kind of money and everything and
then you don't have anything to actually
use it for it so you know spending all
this money but then you don't you can't
can't really do anything with with the
outcome of it uh but if you you know if
you Cobble together your own home lab
made out of like refurbished Hardware
can you imagine if I paid for that thing
new so I refurbished it cost me 1,200
bucks 12 3,300 bucks I don't know how
much it cost let's go look let's go look
it was uh I actually made a video about
it let's go find it again so
Amazon uh it's I hope I don't dox too
much about myself here but oh well
uh I
mean I I am positive I'm doc saying
stuff about myself
hpz
640 I just really hope my address isn't
on there somewhere my wife would be so
mad at me search orders I did okay HP
search orders you're gonna see
everything we ever bought through Amazon
that's how risky I
am yeah God dang it wa am I going to
search this for
computer
computer I didn't spell it
right come on
Rob I can't type this because of the
angle
here God you're gonna see all of my
things that I bought you Canna see all
the money I
waste I I I don't like this itemization
thing maybe I should go back to privacy
mode for a second so you can't see all
of my so far I haven't doxed anything
too badly I
hope um God if they put it if they put a
secure token in the URL I'm goingon to
be
pissed I GNA be really
pissed never put that [__] in query
strings that's like such a major no no
why isn't it showing
it uh
HP uh server
tower all right so the Reliant gen
Z you like my big nose I like your nose
too my big broken
nose my nose got you see how broken it
is yeah I might get a new nose out of
this out of getting out of getting my
teeth knocked out yeah
what what is this one
about hp6 4 Tower ELO Xenon
V3 six cores that's not very many
cores no the one I had had like 50 cores
I
think yeah it was a
z640 I I'm G to find it z640 I have to
find it I already made a video and I
can't remember where it is now here it
is renewed what no that's not it that is
not that does not have there
the one I have had like two like 52 mag
and veram and stuff like that Xenon are
they're cheap p a
lenses really do they that's so cool
um yeah I think I think if you go over
here you can find some of them by the
way I'm not particularly a fan of HP I
just is just I found the biggest amount
of bank for the book but now that it
broke uh I'm not so sure I want to
recommend HP refer
anymore um dual 25 gig Nick and a brand
new I9
yeah I know so but I'm glad you guys are
talking about the the issues involving
buying uh refurbished
Hardware um obviously one of the issues
is it might go dead on you anytime so
you better have a backup of some kind
um that's that's not that much RAM I you
know my system God I've got to find it
I've got to find it I I can't tell you
how much RAM it had in it it was
insane you know what it's in my it's
it's in here
somewhere yeah z uh
HP uh s HBC ml s
Technologies simulating ml
Ops um no that's not it
z640 I wonder if I even wrote anything
about it I
didn't I did I didn't I didn't write
anything about
it that makes me
mad because I I you know what I made a
video about it I did I made a
video did I put a link in the
video in my own video where is it third
computer you should buy there it is
should be a server hey why don't I
actually watch my own video how about
that there you go z640 I didn't put a
link though I got all this stuff in
there there you go yeah somebody people
saying they have different needs no
interested doing that this this was kind
of a trolling reply though by the way
yeah this person says I had a specific
audience and online class he is
addressing no doubt but I but they
obviously someone who happens to find a
video for the first time my point is
simply that this approach isn't for
everyone no it's not but you know that's
you know it's worth look point taken I'm
gonna I'll I'll defer to that person who
said I have a different system and your
recommendation is just for a particular
type of user but that I don't need that
that's the wrong system I'm like okay
but a lot of times when people come to
me they want to know well what's the
best system to get started with for what
you do and they people and and that's
when I make videos I make videos
assuming people are going to do like I
don't know a modicom of research about
where I'm coming from that's why I made
that 10-minute you know summary at the
beginning of the video about the kind of
thing that I'm doing and uh so I'm
getting yeah I'm getting a Vortex
blender overnight so there HP
z640 there it is okay so this is what I
got so for
$735 okay we we have to look at this
again and the reason we have to look at
this again uh I'm going to switch to
small mode so you can see it better um
the reason we have to look at this again
is because we have to decide whether I'm
going to do the hardware route and buy
another one uh which is funny because I
was just going to buy the action five uh
camera which is you know the the kit the
the it'ss like $570 $500 or so and
instead I'm so glad I didn't do that
because that money I can now spend on a
new tower if I need one but we we
haven't decided if we're going to get a
new tower yet and and I know it's going
to take a long time but I'm going to use
as much as this this two hours in this
video as I can evaluating all my options
uh for somebody like me um that is
somebody who wants to specialize in uh
back-end software
development who has already done
everything I need for infrastructure
engineering I have had since you know
for the last 30 years I'm not even
exaggerating I am I doxing my address
there uh which part of it it says
Davidson that's
fine riew my
order I'm looking again I'm looking very
closely to make sure I don't mind doxing
Davidson if it has the
exact if it has my exact street address
then that would be bad I need to know
that so I'm taking a moment to look at
that um just to to to see if that's
true uh if it is true I have to throw
this video away that's fine I I don't
mind doing that either uh but I I I
really want to know because I I
regularly go to Amazon and I want to be
able to go to Amazon cleanly and not
have to worry about everything I I know
that my specific home address does get
doxed when I uh order so when you place
the order that's the screen I don't ever
want to show but this here it says
deliver to Rob Davidson 2306 that that
is not doxing uh my exact location and
people know I live in Davidson already I
I I IRL stream from Davidson literally
every day so um
anyway um okay so enough of that this is
the thing I want to do we get another
one or do we not all right now if you
would ask me this
question uh yeah thank you though ker I
appreciate that um OBS filter that
detects your own info and blurs it out
there's probably something I don't care
about that it would be
hard I just don't want people to know my
EXA and if you did figure it out it
would be fine but I actually stream from
this place before is that okay all right
we're all good uh I'm sorry I'm reading
the chat there people are watching out
for me I appreciate that I really do
thank you very much for watching out for
me um
so again
um if you are just starting
out and and you like to do more than
just
software so I personally think everybody
should build a computer at least once
right I is it required to get a job no
it's abs not required it definitely
isn't you know that's that's not
required you can you can do that um and
so the point I'm trying to make is if
you're just starting out
then it might be better for you and this
is what I used to we used to do this as
skill stack all the time we would have
you know a couple dozen people bring in
computers and you know Grandma's old
computer with taxes on it and we' we'd
wipe the do drive and get to use it I
mean there are computers that are being
wasted in people's corners of their
apartment and their houses all over the
country all over the world and so
finding those and putting Linux on there
and breathing new life and wiping the
drives in a way that you know your aunt
or uncle is going to trust that's the
reason they're hanging on to it by the
way because they don't want to get rid
of it they're too afraid that they're
going to be giving away information so
it goes in the corner of their house
someplace and they totally forget about
it until you ask them right so if that's
the case um and you want to play around
with a lot of Hardware you can probably
get a lot of free hardware and you can
put that all and you can Tinker with it
you can install Linux on there and you
can you know maybe invest some money in
buying a switch and then putting them
all on the switch and then you know
practice your your networking and then
you can build you know you can build an
actual cluster out of those you could
make put those combine those all into
prox MOX as long as you don't get more
than 16 which is what I did I had a
whole bunch of mac Minis and I put more
than 16 and proxo spell on its face so
um um you know there are lots of things
you can do proxmox is a virtualization
manager technology it's a a very popular
um uh non-enterprise uh application for
managing H lab kind of stuff which at
some point we'll talk about if you if
you really want to know about about
things like prox Mox and stuff like that
there are lots of other streamers and
YouTubers who do much better video
content than I will about that um so I'm
not particularly interested in it by the
way um so let's repeat let's repeat what
I'm interested interested in and then
you can decide how you want to di how
you want to divert from what I'm
interested in um again I just want an
Enterprise environment that models the
environment that I am responsible to
work on and to maintain now when I say
work on and maintain my current
responsibilities at work are rather
simple so my current work
responsibilities boil down
to um to me
being uh writing these days writing code
and writing kubernetes deployments and
writing Kat apps and um managing tickets
and and making sure that our notes are
up or if they have problems you know
that they're flapping you know piix some
and then but whenever we have a problem
we hand them off we hand the
infrastructure problems off to the
infrastructure team and we hand off
other problems that are related to um
what I want to say here you know other
problems that are related uh to
networking for example to the network
team and these are all things that in a
smaller in a smaller company you would
be responsible for and you could
actually work with and I had done that
in the past I mean in you know depending
on where you work you might be the
entire one person it shop and if that's
you then maybe that's the lab you want
but in my case I don't want that right
the the only thing I want is I want a
reliable uh
set of systems that mimic as close as
possible uh the systems that I am
responsible for so my primary
responsibility going into this going
into 2025 and the end of
2024 is completing and maintaining and
adding observability to our high
performance machine learning API which
is I'm very proud to say is is keeping
over over a 100 I think at this point
we're a thousand over 100 h 100s Each of
which is
$25,000 uh busy and so my my the
software that I've written with that I
mean that my my peers and I have written
um keeps that stuff running you know our
team is keeping that that very very
expensive Hardware busy I can't buy that
Hardware I can't I can't even dream of
renting a B100 is even to rent to V1 100
is like a thousand a month so I mean
these are very expensive systems and I
work for a company that has more
computing power than
probably I've actually heard that
unofficially if our company was actually
public about its Computing capacity it
would be within the top five of the
world and its Computing capacity and I
don't please don't guess where I work um
it's pretty surprising it's pretty
surprising that the company that I work
for has that much Computing capacity and
is putting it into good work all the
time and very happy to say that the
software I've been writing and testing
and need to improve upon is is is
helping with that so people will use our
our you know our app API and they'll
they'll submit their applications via
the API and it will go into the system
and Via PB PB uh PBS which is actually a
really good
um thing that I'm taking note of because
I I need to simulate PBS on our systems
I need to I need to create a fully
simulated PBS uh batch processing system
in addition to kubernetes so that I can
emulate our batch processing systems um
and I don't know how much because we
we've customized a lot of it we have
some pretty big names working for our
company including the people who
originally wrote the the PBS
software um if you don't know what what
what uh batch processing is I mean we
can go look it up really quick but the
only reason it's relevant for the home
lab talk is is can I run this on my lab
uh open PBS yep um open PBS is is the
the the closest U
one to it um and this is uh this has
become
uh biting my tongue here
um I don't I have to be careful here
because some of this stuff borders on
intellectual property because yeah I you
know if I
so let's how do I put this if I if
I make my if I if I build a home lab
that very directly
emulates uh how our company has
strategically
deployed high performance
Computing
um I don't know at what point I'm giving
away our Trade Secrets and I have to be
careful with that just the use the fact
that we even use PBS you know let me
just I'm going to briefly talk about
that it is relevant to this home lab
conversation
um because you know a lot of people uh
particularly on Twitch uh but definitely
on YouTube talk about where they work
all the time
and uh they give very specific examples
um you know I I'm not I don't have a
problem with it I just I just feel
like uh sometimes it borders on
a violation of trade secret uh IP law uh
in fact I was very concerned the prim
agan you guys know Prime um and uh
lately you know Prime and I have tried
to help each other out a little bit um
he's much obviously he's a huge streamer
and he seeks to be a huge streamer I do
not um I want to talk about this briefly
though because he in one of his
microservices video he very very
specific specifically started drawing
all of his compon a few times he was
more abstract about it but he he made a
full
diagram of the infrastructure required
for um an episode of Black Mirror that
caused a lot of problems and it was
related to the microservices meme and I
don't want to get too far off topic here
but the fact that he was putting that
into his video um made me aware that I
need to be careful that I'm not doing
something similar and and you know I I
don't know what their policy is on that
but in my world the way I was raised you
know even telling somebody where you
worked in a pub was considered something
that you would get you know an HR
violation so we live in a different time
and and I I admit I'm old um but you
know people regularly talk about their
companies they use it as an opportunity
to I mean there ala 4 does the same
thing he's very open with the company he
works for and talks about it openly and
it says what strategy they've used even
very specifically outlines their
security
strategies and in my world in my world
that is like such a no no um so anyway
so why is it relevant to the Homeland
because as I'm building out the home lab
for you know one of the top five highest
performing high performance Computing
machine learning labs in the
world um you know I could be divulging
something so the takeaway for you the
reason you care is because if you're
building a home lab and you're doing it
live and you're doing it publicly you
probably want to be careful that you
don't end up D
divulging um corporate Trade Secrets uh
I'm actually streaming with the mic on
right now just to let you know uh I I
can move if you want but um I'm just
letting you know I had we have a m mysty
guest is M my guest is over here
so I had to bring attention to it
because I really did you know
me I can't stop we need to go get pizza
again by the
way people ask where's Mr guest all the
time I'm I'm tell
anyway that's okay my steps on my guest
um all right so where are we let's go
back to the home laap thing let's get
let's get on with it so we need to make
a decision whether we're going to buy
Hardware or whether we're going to buy
um whether we're going to do software so
um let's go ahead and
um look at the breakdown MoneyWise shall
we so let's do that what is our
budget so my budget is uh I'm either GNA
be that's why I wanted to show the the
hardware because let's add it up
um so okay so here we go we've
got uh we we collect your own Hardware
we talked about doing that we talked
about using the cloud for everything um
actually we haven't talked about that we
will talk about that let's talk about
simulating hardware virtualization
containerization um so getting your own
Hardware
um and so what are what are the
requirements let's see what are my
requirements right what what are my
requirements all right and I'm actually
going to go ahead and write my personal
requirements my uh personal
requirements uh I need to uh be able be
able to run open
PBS
um and let's see be able
to um
emulate
kubernetes uh prod Dev and imp uh
clusters
and uh let's see what else I don't need
to do any
networking um I need to be able to
emulate
anible uh are uh anible uh
cluster
deployment um
automations um it would be nice if I
could integrate with
GitHub I don't think does anybody know
if it's even possible to
um is it even possible to run to emulate
GitHub actions at
home and to set up your own GitHub
actions Runners I don't think it's
possible
right I don't know let's
see um is it possible to
have my own selfhosted
Runners for GitHub
actions uh that run in my home
lab it is possible I haven't I haven't
done it is it the same thing we we use
custom Runners for our company is it the
same thing so are you saying are you to
re other way are are you saying that
custom ERS apply to people as well as
they do to Enterprise so GitHub
Enterprise cloud is not required is that
what you're saying use that to configure
your network stuff damn today I learned
I did not I am using that for everything
I I cannot believe I haven't been doing
that oh my God okay um uh with
custom oh my God I see this is why I
live stream this is why I live stream
because all you smart smart people you
you know who you are I'm not going to
dox you you can come in here and tell me
I'm PLL it you know with it and give me
ideas this is a great idea possible to
have your own s Runners for get of
actions that run your home lab a s post
Runner is an environment where you can
run I I imagine that that includes web
Hooks and stuff
right right um so uh running your home
lifeb a cost Runner is environment where
you can run your GitHub access workflow
using your own Hardware such as in your
home lab instead of github's cloud cloud
hosted
Runners Custom Custom environments you
can configure the runner to have
specific software Hardware configuration
network access running your home lab uh
Hardware or private networks wow cost
effective can save money Computer
Resources in your home
lab yes yes yes you don't have like
because you you end up paying Runner
resource oh my God this is so cool
this you know what this means this means
I can make my home
lab I can do a PR request or PLL and I
can trigger a zcas and Generator that
populates a web page or something rather
than using the automated you know I'm
just using static pay generation right
now but you could you could trigger your
own stic site gener somebody out there
is like yeah Rob Where Have You
Been yeah yeah now I know um increase
control you can you can control when the
how to host the runners and be able to
scale uh steps to set up hey thanks for
the follow Miss Lin um prepare your home
lab machine Ure that machine in the home
lab has the necessary resources and that
is why I asked the question because I'm
about to make a home lab right ensure
that machine in your home lab has the
necessary resources CPU memory dis space
to run workloads you plan to execute VI
of actions s Runner should have network
access to GitHub for fetching
repositories and ping
results uh can it be a virtualized
machine we don't know virtual machine
create a GitHub repo you can run the
self register yourself Runner
GitHub uh go to action Runners add
Runner there got to be some way for it
to get to it it's got to be able to have
a web hook or something that you expose
somehow and that you can probably do
through cloudfire or something uh
download the runner
software configure the Runner after
telling the runner you need to configure
the runner get able provideed tokens
part of the runner setup place it in
your
repo run the Runner start the runner as
a service make sure your Runner
continues to run in the background start
as a
service actually it it looks like it
doesn't have to have an inbound access
to your network it dials outbound oh Moz
is that what you're saying you're
confirming okay yeah I was going to say
that that is a much safer approach than
it's just it's dialing in oh my God this
is so cool I'm so glad we you guys told
me about this it pulls the job to run
yeah that is so cool um use yourself on
run work you know what's really cool
about this is that at work I I
specifically have to be able to make my
own Runners so um I haven't had to make
a runner yet for the stuff that we're
doing but being able to make a runner
and do it in the home lab so that that
is definitely a thing I want to do
um so can I do that
on in the
cloud I imagine that means you could do
it from the cloud too so so let's uh all
right I think let's let's let's wrap up
we're an hour in we only got an hour
left so let's let's wrap up what the
personal requirements are for me now
your your requirements might jive with
mine but so I need to be able to open
kubernetes and imp clusters that's the
main thing actually I need to be able to
uh be able to to uh to to test uh
actually to uh be able to test U uh
Enterprise uh
API uh
development uh Enterprise backend
Enterprise
elment and this this this is an
interesting part right here
because it's a VI it would be a it some
of that code if I put it on my home lab
as a violation of of
policy um
but testing out
techniques uh for example the uh using
SSH as a as a transport um for the API
when you don't have another method of
doing that because you can't run
microservices on the target um those
techniques can be tested um without
giving away you know without violating
uh corporate policy with regard to
putting you know corporate software
which I do not intend to do uh on my own
stuff um there is a lot of software that
I write by the way that um can live it
is something that I can actually write
that can be public that can be used so
for example the Y Lo stuff that I'm
writing uh I've I've already I I know
legally it would probably be in trouble
if this ever came to it but I
have uh already written a lot of that
software and it is deployed and it is
working at work um but I also want
something similar to that and so I am
writing
uh almost the same software from scratch
that does the same thing uh for myself
and it's got a different organization
and everything but at some point if that
becomes false approved I can actually
swap out the stuff that I'm using at
work for the stuff that I write when
it's all open source approved and for
those of you who work for companies that
are uh that are open source friendly you
know what I'm talking about um a lot of
times they you will start out writing a
library and make it public from the
beginning but a lot of times it's like
Google was with kubernetes and ISO they
it takes them a long time to warm up to
the idea of giving their software away
and when they finally do then you
realize you didn't really want it anyway
because it's
crap I'm speaking specifically of the
kubernetes code base it's one of the
worst code bases I have ever seen um
it's absolutely horrible and it's like
what it's exactly what you would expect
bunch of Junior Java developers uh to
write their go in you don't believe me
let me show I I'll I'll show you the
function that's like 40 40 characters
long or so it's it's it's insane I I
don't like it I'm I'm I'm done okay so
um to be able to test back at Enterprise
API
development run open PPS uh be able to
emulate anible cluster deployment
automations uh I'm not going to be
running open shift there is a team that
is using open shift at our at our place
but we are not we are kubernetes from
scratch uh now this this let's talk
about the from scratch thing this is
this is a very key point when you're
making a decision about whether to go
with Hardware or Cloud so there are
certain things that you
cannot emulate in the
cloud and let me let me say what I mean
by that without going into a full-blown
kuber
explanation um if you are going to
deploy a ku's cluster in the same way
that I we we've deployed it at work or
that many Enterprises have deployed
in-house that means they built their own
vanilla kubernetes clusters from
scratch um they've had to make choices
kubernetes is a specification it is not
a
software uh it's not a software suite
and while certain pieces of that I mean
you can go to the kubernetes uh where is
it let's go out there for a
second
um uh what's it what is the road
map it's not is it called the road map I
think it is yeah so no that's not it
this is the educational thing it's
called something else
um I God I can't remember the URL this I
haven't looked it in a long time
kubernetes landscape I think it
is yes this is it
CIA and there I just heard a streamer
today talking about how much they don't
like kubernetes in fact they in his
Twitter feed I won't say who it is in
his Twitter feed he he made a
notification saying that he just deleted
kubernetes from his home lab and never
putting it back because his current job
doesn't require using it anymore um
there's a fair amount of hate against
kubernetes lately and and you know while
I don't disagree with most of the
criticisms of kubernetes it's not going
anywhere and there's still a lot of good
jobs in it that are
unfilled um how you doing culus so um so
as you can see I mean Helm is a disaster
don't even touch it in fact one of the
thing reasons I want to do this is
because I'm flattening Helm charts for
Harbor and and be installing Harbor into
my home lab and testing you know how
that how that is is is happening so that
I can do something similar at work um
but yeah so as you can see there's a
bunch of Technologies here um that
fulfill uh what is needed for kubernetes
so let me give you a specific example
with regard
to uh your home lab so if you're going
to build a kubernetes home lab and and
there's lots and lots of videos of me
trying to do this from before A lot of
you would remember them LBG will
definitely remember um you have to make
you have to make decisions you have to
make a decision like what is going to
what's my networking interface going to
be you know the cni and usually it's
Calico what is my uh storage driver
going to be what is my load balancer
going to be what you know and that's
usually like something like metal lb um
how am I going to apply policies am I
going to use you know gatekeeper am I
going to do there's just a ton of like
decisions that you have to make four am
I going to use Cube bird or am I going
to have some sort of Hardware load
balancer so you know at home you're not
going to have that kind of option um You
probably end up using round robin DNS um
you know you've got a lot of decisions
be made what storage class is a big one
right so kubernetes doesn't come with
any idea with any notion of storage uh
other than what you tell it and the
default is Local Host storage which
means it just uses whatever dis the node
is has got available to it which is a no
no you're not supposed to do that unless
unless it's a very very very specific uh
um use case and you have a Damon set or
something that's going to always be on
the same machine and for performance
reasons you want the you know the
storage cost to be local as opposed to
PBC which is distri I mean there's just
it's just a mess kuber kubernetes is
really really hard to get your your head
around um but why is that relevant to
the home lab because uh a lot of people
going into kues like me uh when I did
several years ago and I'm still not a
pro kubernetes because I'm always doing
the software development on the back end
for the API stuff which isn't even kuber
related at all um and so I'm you know my
mind is kind of split between multiple
things and I tend to preper the go
programming so you know my kubernetes
skills are soft that's why I want a home
lab so so having said that how much
kubernetes skill do I need right how
much do you need do I need to be able to
deploy a kubernetes from scratch vanilla
cluster and understand the networking
related ISS issues do I have to be able
to understand you know lad balancing am
I going to be talking about VPN sorts of
things am I going to do virtual land
networking so you know there is a
kubernetes skill set and a you know a
module uh sort of an educational module
I would say that if that you need to
address if you want to be on the
infrastructure side in which case and
that's the lab that's why I built the
lab by the way um
so uh the lab that I donated and I'm I'm
glad I'm thinking about this because the
reason I donated the lab um was because
I made a decision as we were doing the
move I mean I I invested a lot of money
in building up that lab based on one
assumption the Assumption was that I
wanted to be a kick-ass infrastructure
engineer who could deploy and
troubleshoot uh nodes and devices and
gpus
and you know the utilization of gpus
taints and tolerations um GPU node
Discovery all all of this stuff at the
kubernetes meets Hardware level right in
fact it was at that time that I was
evaluating in fact I took they took my
comment down from the website I was one
of the early evaluators of um one of I
forget the name of it now I can't
remember it's blanking on it's covid
brain I have C brain um the T tar what
it starts with a t
there's a there's a Linux T tals tals
that's it I was one of the early
evaluators of tals about two years ago
and that tals was this idea of like
Hardware management through you know
kubernetes which um I they're still
trying to push it really big in fact
Google uh Mr Mr go himself Mr Cobra
who's over evangelizing go for Google
and is pushing it tell us a lot uh a lot
these days um and uh I mean for good
reason I mean
but anyway
so that was when I was like okay I need
to be really good with installing and
setting up Hardware uh I didn't good
with specking computers uh I I ended up
finding out that my my disc drives were
too slow for
etcd uh and so I got some faster you
know we did the IPP check against the
faster um you know SSD of the Optiplex
that I bought for $150 and so I I got
three of those so that I could simulate
you know
haed um and you know make sure
everything worked and you know the
Quorum would work out and everything and
and and actually have a true kubernetes
deployment even if uh the storage
classes in fact I ended up leaving that
when we were trying to discuss what what
kind of storage class I was going to end
up using and I people were saying you
should use SE sefs and you should do
this and uh you know I was like can I
just use NFS and they're like no it's
got problems and at work we were having
massive failures with gpfs and now
everybody's all luster and now they're
going back uh to gpfs because there have
been improvements in the gpfs stack so a
lot of work I mean just just the topic
of how do I I mean this is this is the
question it's a very simple question how
do I add storage to my kubernetes
cluster right it should be easy enough
to answer it is not it is not it's
probably the most complicated piece of
kubernetes because kubernetes does keeps
trying to say there's no such thing as
storage and the only way you would even
see any of these problems is if you were
to try to do it by yourself if you go to
the cloud if you go up to Google cloud
or you go up to Amazon or Azure any of
them eks you all of them they all do
this for you their kubernetes
deployments already have their own
implementation of storage class and you
don't it's all invisible it's invisible
to you you don't care you don't care and
it's in the spe from kubernetes you
should never have to care about how much
storage you have well I had to care
because all of a sudden our disc was
filled and we had no way to know when it
was going to get filled don't get me
started on that and there was nothing in
it and the most recent version of
kubernetes have added storage metrics uh
that are now part of the standard
kubernetes uh you know software thing
thank God because you know people
actually do care people who are doing
their own vanilla deployments need to
know about that stuff but strictly
speaking you not you don't really need
to know whether you're feeling your PVC
or how how it's you know manifesting
behind the scenes because kues was
supposed to be this you know beautiful
abstraction over all of that stuff well
if you're managing all of that stuff and
you're also deploying the abstraction on
top of all of that stuff then you need
to know about all of those things what
does this have to do with a home lab
because it radically changes your
approach to how you have a home lab I
cannot make a home lab that emulates
everything I can't put gpfs custs and
some of that stuff I definitely can't
put some of the higher end Nvidia gpus
this is because one of the reasons that
I wanted to use those Mac minis because
they had GPU and then I learned that
Nvidia didn't have drivers that
supported the GPU on those Mac minis
because they were so old and not they
didn't even support I had I I bought um
like two or three uh what are they for
IRL streaming those uh those Jets and
Nanos which have you know cacor on there
but they're also not supported therefore
because there's no drivers you can't use
them and like why would you want GPU on
your kubernetes because machine learning
High Performance Machine learning being
able to kick off jobs that have taints
and tolerations that that match them
that create affinities for specific gpus
that are in the cluster as opposed to in
PBS or some sort of batch processing we
have both right most of our most of our
high-end machine learning stuff goes
through our own you know customized
batch processing system but we have for
the longest time have also been sending
things forward to and kubernetes didn't
have any notion of GPU when it first
started and now they're like oh [__] Ai
and so they're adding it to it like hand
over fist you're getting their kuber is
becoming more and more aware of GPU and
so now you can submit kuber deployments
and stuff you can create T of to and say
okay make sure I have GPU over here
because this particular job is going to
run over here needs there's deployment
there whatever it needs to have you know
a
GPU okay how does that relate to my home
lab do I need to emulate running machine
learning models in my home
lab and that that is a question I have
right uh do I
need uh ml model uh model um model
jobs at
home now
this you know in kubernetes
right in batch
if if I was going to make a an actual if
I'm going to if I was going to create an
actual emulation of of my work
environment I would have that
stuff
right if I wanted to if I wanted to so
this API step right here right if I
wanted to create an API that emulated
submission of machine learning jobs that
run under PBS or some form of
PBS um I'm answering my own question
here because I can't I obviously I can't
I can't use our customized version of
PBS batch processing uh in my home lab I
can use open PBS and I can create my own
thing that may be similar but I cannot
use the actual code I just can't that
that is a highly highly competitive
trade secret within our company uh our
customized version of PBS uh they
actually head hunted the original
creators of PBS who work for our company
now uh in order to keep us competitive
so I me really really Kick-Ass
competitive like better than anybody in
the planet right now you know my my the
company I work for kind of like looks
down its nose at bank
companies because it's like okay yeah
run along go play with your search
engine uh and and so anyway uh do how
much of that do I want to emulate how
much can I emulate what what am I going
to be doing in my home lab right um and
and so you know
I I got to think about this I'm I'm like
pondering right
now
um
so yeah
I the thing that gets me in trouble
every time I do any of this is I always
Pi I always take on too much it's just
how I am I always you know humans
naturally are overly optimistic about
everything um everything I mean that's
why they say every estimate you ever
make you should always double it um
because we generally are about 50% wrong
in our optimism of how long something
takes uh uh or or what you know um you
know what we're going to what we're
going to do with it and
and and I
um you know that's what got me in
trouble that's why I end up donating the
lab because I was like I thought that I
wanted to if you look at my calendar I
don't have any time if I'm going to
maintain an 8 hour
workday uh you know
and it's not like I'm trying to break
into the industry at this point I am
like gonna retire in 10 five to 10 years
so if anything I'm maintaining the
skills I have
so my needs are different than yours if
you're trying to break in you probably
have a lot more to learn you maybe have
more time than I do you're going to
dedicate you know 102 16 24 hours
outside of work uh to learn all the
things you need to I don't need to do
that I am maintaining the skills that I
have and um sharpening those specific
skills so that I remain the best at what
I can what I am
doing um so that I do not get distracted
by all the tech out there one of the
biggest mistakes I think Mo any
technologist can make is try to learn
everything all at once and then you're
then you're not good at anything now
there is this idea of this bull stack
engineer which is a total myth but um
even in a full stack engineer you
generally get you know database SQL
Specialists and you get people that are
API Specialists and you get people that
are front-end developers you get people
who are really kickass with react you
get people who are just really really
good with Dynamic CSS
um so having a specialization is going
to make you more in demand when somebody
wants the skill you have so that's just
a general piece of advice is you know if
you want to get a job become the best at
something I mean seriously like Target
find what it is and Target that thing
and become a 10x in that one thing and
then Market the [__] out of that when
you go out because that you can then
prove that you are literally
you know one of the top people on the
planet in that specific thing and that's
why I think lead C tests are so stupid
because they're now you're the best in
the planet at doing a lead Code test but
you haven't produced anything um so you
know but if you can prove that you can
produce something really well um and how
how so let me let me talk about that how
that works for myself here just doing a
little bit of
reflection um currently Beyond education
which is obviously my passion and my one
of my my superpowers um but at this job
within the scope of my current job uh
it's funny because we just I just had a
performance review in a one-on-one and
or getting ready for a performance
review and I I we had a talk I had to
kind of do some reflection like how can
I bring the most value to this company
and um there's actually two things
specifically and I'm I'm talking about
myself here because I encourage you to
do the same thing when you're thinking
about where to put the time in the home
lab right and this this is directly
related to the decision about whether I
should get a computer or I should use
the cloud and I think you probably can
guess where I'm going with this but as
you know the new because I was you know
I started out as a generalized
infrastructure engineer and stuff and
then I obviously I kind of fell into
this role because I had the skill I I
clearly I'm the subject matter expert on
our team and go period And I'm not
saying that to brag I just had the most
experience in it I I I picked it up in
13 because I knew it was going to be
something I wanted to do uh but but
particularly for systems integration on
the back end I don't have I'm not as
strong with some of the cloud related
things such as you know I had to learn
ooth really well um which was pain in
the ass by the way um I still had to
pick up get up actions and workflows and
things like that that are part of
development if you're going to be doing
API development I had to pick up apog
and and open API which is the you know
formally Swagger all those things that
that you know Cloud developers would
Norm have I had to pick those pieces up
to have them go with with go but now go
has become my core skill the reason I'm
saying this is the only thing I need to
be able to do is write go applications
and deploy them to ket's Cluster and
have them talk to uh either actual or
simulated PBS
systems that's it so that means I
need
um uh
uh I'm going to make a conclusion here
uh only
simulated uh systems are
required I'm not going to be doing any
performance
benchmarking um and uh
yeah oh that is cool uh
yeah home lab subreddit should be
helpful yeah subreddit or I also have I
mean there's a Discord Channel about
this um
only simulated systems are
required this is going to be very
tempting okay so we have a half an hour
left and I want to make a decision about
this the reason so at the beginning of
this at the beginning of the stream I
told you my sad story about killing my
tower uh you know let it rest in peace
uh I don't know how I killed it I moved
it and it shorted the motherboard
somehow and now the Fan's going to blow
up I mean the fan sounds like the
computer's going to blow up every time I
turn it on and I don't frankly I don't
get if if I was in my 20s I would be in
there I would I would have a post board
I'd be checking the post you know things
I would be like you know sometimes maybe
even soldering a broken connection
because I'm you got a using a computer
from somebody's grandma or something
that I don't care about that anymore
okay um I gota be honest you went for an
interview they wanted back DB cyber
devops
testing yeah they always they want
everything right they want the they want
the all stack
engineer
um yeah and and frankly you know even
even the most experienced people aren't
going to have all that stuff they're not
you know how you know how I couldn't
even do a kubernetes get pods command
the other day I've done it thousands of
them all the time but I couldn't do it
because I've been so focused also I had
Co but I had been so Focus focused on um
you know go for this entire time you you
can't Conta switch all the time and keep
all the stuff at least I can't may maybe
there's maybe some of you have more like
onboard Ram than than others I don't I
don't maybe it's because I'm old I don't
know but I that's why I have a zle
casting by the way if you're having
problem with content switching one of
the best ways to bolster yourself is to
add your own Ram add your own Ram in the
form of a second brain a zetoc Casten or
something like that then you can go
fetch that data anytime you want when
you have the thought you capture the
thought right away before you forget it
because you're going to forget it I do
it all the time and you can have it over
there and you can go fetch that this is
one of the reasons that I love Chad GPT
so much because Chad GPT has largely
been populated with all of the onboard
cash of any question I might ever have
like I couldn't even remember like you
know whatever so you the point's been
made um needed 20 years experience
exactly a few T few to crabs to Chrome
tabs less dopamine addiction don't give
into that dopamine addiction more yoga
practice meditation you know calm the
monkey mind do do exercise I mean this
is not about that but um this is about
getting to what I need and what I need
is a system I can write and develop the
API on the system that I can practice uh
doing the deployments the system and
that includes uh GitHub actions for uh
triggered deployments and stuff and and
how to have anible actually call into a
GI up action um and stuff like that so
that means I have need to have multiple
machines uh the machines can be
virtualized they do not need there's
another thing uh I do not need um uh GPU
capacity uh I um a lot of GPU capacity
in
cluster or PBS or back
patch now that said I probably do want
it that this is a really important
question because um only one process can
use your GPU at a time um
and I found this out the hard way on my
main machine I have a my desktop hard
this is one of the things I'm thinking
about doing I have a I have a desktop a
dis up Windows machine that I've been
streaming from and I'm not using it
anymore because of the using these Max
for everything uh the only time I use it
is when I'm doing IRL streaming and it's
a Windows machine currently um because I
was going to play zift on there but I
don't need to do that anymore because I
can do zift on the Mac here and stream
from here and I can so I don't need it
for the reason I which means that I can
now Boot the you know I need to migrate
Anton off of there which is a virtual
machine over there right now and I need
to get the uh anything from this whip
configuration or the
uh this stuff up that's Windows machine
and I can reimage that machine as a
server and it is a pretty big S that
might be a waste it's a big ass
GPU um it's not a GPU that's designed
it's a GPU designed for game game
playing it's not a GPU designed for
machine learning models so you know it
would be it would sort of
be uh a waste of that computer uh to not
use a desktop environment on it of some
kind uh whether it be Linux uh or um you
know I I ran Linux as a desktop
environment on it for years it's funny
because Prime oh my God so the prim agan
yesterday while he was streaming
somebody was giving him [__] for screen
ripping and I was like ah NVIDIA drivers
on Linux and I I remember all the pain
and suffering I went through four years
ago four years ago when I started
streaming four years ago when I started
streaming I said I'm going to stream
from Linux godamn it and everybody was
complaining about the screen ripping and
it took me like two weeks to figure out
how to get rid of the proper NV video
configurations to avoid screen tearing
and somebody was complaining about
screen tearing on Prime stream just this
last week and I was reminded oh my God
that's like one other thing that I don't
have to mess with because I'm streaming
from an actual machine that works not
Linux
desktop um a a A40 does well nice
uh Nvidia Nvidia card supports Sr on
Linux vgpu driver you competition GPU
and passes reversal PC device o that's
very
nice um so you're saying you can
actually chop up a rather powerful GPU
and have it look like multiple gpus for
the sake of uh because then I can assign
each of those gpus off to a a system so
that can't be virtualized what you're
saying
right um is there a minimum version of
of a GPU that can do that because when
I'm I don't I'm pretty confident that my
desktop Windows machine that I'm
streaming you know IRL streaming from is
probably not capable of that I have a
feeling I'm going to have to be buying
an Nvidia GPU for that so I I think I
think we we don't have a lot of time
left we only have like 20 or 30 minutes
here um there's one last thing that we
have to totally rule out and and I don't
like what I'm about to say but there's a
chance that I can do all of this in the
cloud and every time I look at this I
come back and I'm like what the hell was
I
thinking
and but but before the last time I did a
cloud evaluation so let's let's spend
the final moments here okay so we know
it can be virtualized
right um we know it can be virtualized I
do not need a lot of GPU capacity but it
would be nice to at least have one GPU
that I could practice machine learning
model submissions on right I don't want
to become a machine learning Master but
knowing how to submit a machine learning
model uh is probably going to become
more and more general knowledge that
everybody should have so that includes
me and frankly I would like to learn a
little machine learning but you know I
also like to you learn a bit better
better networking those things are very
dangerous because they distract you from
the thing that's going to make you money
that you want to do every day and unless
you want to be a generalist and there
are some people who are that um I the
the people who are machine learning
experts in my experience and I they're
hundreds of them in my workplace they
tend to be very neop fites when it comes
to Linux one of them didn't even know
how to use the MV command they actually
went out to their they were using they
were demonstrating something and they
actually went out to their desktop
browser to their to their whatever their
finder and they copied the file over
rather than using the move command even
though they were all their other
commands with the command they had no
idea to use it they had never learned
Linux terminal but they were phds in
machine learning models because again
they were specialized they put their you
know they put all their brain power into
one bucket in their you know roleplaying
Adventure character
Generation Um so it depends on your
clouds your depends on your Cloud Nest
Egg AKA discretionary money spend that
you don't about yeah CA Mak you pay for
like everything days spend the money on
the right to write it off as business
spense
yeah um
if it is GeForce in the name not a
chance uh the others are at least ampere
GA 10x series four years ago some chance
uhhuh
um
yeah so let's let's think let's talk
about this GPU thing since we're kind of
on it for a second obviously having GPU
in your cluster in your batch system uh
is necessary for emulating machine
learning model submission even if it
only runs on the one GPU
um to be honest when I consider our jobs
most of our machine learning recat jobs
uh they
they uh associate with a single machine
with a GPU and then they lock that GPU
down it's very it's very un there are a
couple applications in our environment
where they they split
up uh different parts of the model to to
different gpus but for the most most
part they want to lock down some of our
most powerful gpus for a very long time
because they need to run them and it's
extremely
expensive um
and the reason I say that is because if
I want a GPU in my system that I can
emulate jobs submission for having one
GPU on a reasonably decent ml processing
GPU on one machine is going to be enough
so whether that's because I've
virtualized a machine and I've assigned
the GPU to that machine which I know you
can do in
kbm
um whether I I want to Chunk Up the GPU
and have it split across multiple ones
it would actually be really nice
somebody in the chat has suggested
that's possible um I probably don't need
that why is that relevant to my home lab
because if I can get away if Nvidia is
going if my machine learning jobs will
run intensive loaded pytorch
if they will run on the GPU that I have
now on my Windows machine if I repurpose
it as a Linux
machine and I can also run I can also
get maybe 10 other BMS out of that
machine I probably could do that now
that you know that CPU and RAM are not
locked down which is amazing actually
the fact that you can actually over
allocate RAM for for to
machines uh I don't think we have any
npus
no I don't have any of that in my system
that I have to emulate anyway somebody
else might but I don't have that right
my the stuff I have to be able to do is
I have to be able to write code and
stuff that gets jobs to their
destination it doesn't even have to be a
real job it could just be the simulation
of a job right but the problem is
simulation is the more you simulate
things for your own test environment um
the more you run into other problems but
this could actually be good because one
of the one of the the the bullet points
of of tasks that I need to do over the
next this year and next is we need to
start creating some really highlevel
high level systems integration testing
for the entire API system that means you
know complete testing of the whole
system and that means running multiple
little things that are checking in with
all the little points of observability
while they're happening and seeing that
everything everything is doing what it's
supposed to do in in terms of like the
scope of the API submission so that
would mean checking in with the job and
seeing if it's doing its thing uh we
have our own load balancer and stuff
like that to make sure that you know
we're allocating we have a our own
failover so that if some of the transfer
nodes are down you know it'll pick up
the next transfer node that's available
um those are all stuff that had to be
hardcoded we had to we had to write our
own for that so so that's the stuff that
I'm focused on testing and and and I can
test all of that um with a job that is
just a simulated machine learning job I
don't even need a GPU I could submit a
simulated machine learning job uh to A
system that only has a CPU and then I
can unless I'm trying to to test you
know taints and tolerations affinities
in my kubernetes cluster for the things
that have GPU which is a configuration
setup operations type of thing that I
might also want to be able to do
um you know all of that would be
facilitated by having I I think I could
do all of that with probably a dozen VMS
that I could you know set up and tear
down one of the goals that I have is I
want to be able to reuse the
infrastructure uh for anything so I want
to be able this we actually are setting
this up in our cluster our our next
cluster deployment this I don't know if
this is a trade secret or not but um our
next cluster deployment model which will
be done by the end of the year um we
Chang we changed something in a repo and
and put it all in the pr process and
everything and then when it gets merged
it automatically redeploys the whole
cluster the entire cluster so it'll
it'll it'll downgrade the cluster it'll
bring it down and it'll bring it back up
slowly with all the new stuff and uh
that's pretty damn cool and and there's
a lot of ansible involved there um the
idea of being able to do that in my own
environment is very appealing to me
uh because then I can just reuse the
same resources the same problem that I
have at home because I don't have a
really big lab is the same problem that
an Enterprise has a scale because they
don't have you know they don't want to
they don't want to waste nodes
particularly those that have very
expensive gpus associated with them I
mean those nodes when they're down it
literally costs us thousands of dollars
a day of outage uh when those things can
are not working uh because we have
enough work to keep every one of our our
high-end gpus uh busy
247 and and sometimes those things are
just sitting idle because they're not
they're for whatever reason hasn't been
matched up so I need to be able to test
that um
so can that be tested with a bunch of
cloud things let's look at cost of cloud
before we end here today um and the the
the thing that got me thinking about I
might be able to afford a cloud
deployment for this kind of thing um so
when when when when you talk about Cloud
the the first thing you want to make a
decision on and I and I am not a cloud
expert at all there are so many better
people about that um who can tell us
what to do and who generally use the
cloud for everything
um again our company has a full GPU uh
deployment um we are gcp that's not a
secret and Google cloud and Google cloud
is is the preferred platform for all
applications development uh within our
company and the only time that they come
to our team is when they realize that
it's too expensive
because it is right it's more expensive
the crazy or they have oh my God I have
some I don't know if I can talk about
this let me think about
this okay so remember I said our company
has a gcp first
policy right I I'm G to zoom in on this
I have I'm going to make up I'm going to
tell you a story so here comes a
story this story might actually make the
decision for me it really might okay
so let me tell you a
story
so since the dawn of time companies have
been saying let's do it all inhouse and
save
money whether it means the people that
they hire you know whether they hire
contractors or they hire internal people
or they want to build out infrastructure
internally this pendulum has been
swinging very slowly since computers
were well frankly since network
computing was
invented and I have been around through
every iteration of this I I remember
attending things in the 90s
where everybody's desktop PCS were going
to be obliterated and network it was all
about the network computer anybody
remember this anybody remember the sun
Microsystems Network computer and they
were trying to convince businesses to
commit to this thing this this little
itsy bitsy teeny tiny box that would go
on your on your desktop and then and
then you know fast forward to 2020 one
or whatever and and what Google tried to
do by saying hey you can just play any
computer game and run it all on our back
end and you can just have the screen
right and all the backend power is going
to be you can have a nice Thin Client so
thick client Thin Client Thin Client th
you know Cloud not Cloud on Prem on PR
this this pendulum has been swinging
forever uh netx yeah neix tried to down
the path and and frankly they really
don't make sense unless you're talking
about University deployment you know
pixie booting uh you know uh that book
try this this pendulum keeps going like
this right so and you know I'm now
full-time and so it's kind of
interesting because one of the while the
pendulum about all our resources are
going to be HR they're all going to be
hired internally can be swinging inside
you can have another pendulum all the
way out here so one of our pendulums is
and I won't say that the company I'm
almost did our company is focused on in
building internal resources they're
getting rid of all the contractors and I
was a contractor and they had to make a
decision do we firey him or keep him and
they said well no we got to keep this
guy so so that was good but then he got
over here you got over here they made
another decision they said no more of
this Enterprise infrastructure on site
we we want to get rid of it it's too
expensive we we can't keep it around and
we you know we we can't buy it it just
gets immediately you know out of date so
and it's not even the latest so we're
just going to and we rent half of our
Hardware anyway because you know we
don't want to be on the hook for it when
it if it's not real plus some of the
hardware we have has never been released
to the general pop public because we
have a very very very close relationship
with Nvidia because they they want us to
test all their stuff up first because
because we put everything through the
paces like crazy uh same with IBM that's
why we found all the GPS problems uh PFS
problems anyway so and and so that
pendulum's like no no no more on on Prem
we're going to put it all in the cloud
so then we get this mandate at the
beginning of the year everything is
going to gcp if you're not going to
gcp you're a bad
person and here here's our team which
our team is responsible for running all
the internal um uh basically the
internal Cloud when there's two internal
clouds it's really complicated we also
have an entire team that does an open
shift internal thing we don't have
anything to do with them we it's a big
company so we have this internal you
know we're specifically for High
Performance Machine learning so we
provide internal resources for that and
so sure enough here's the story it keeps
swinging back and forth um your local
librated that when it was a kid BT 100
oh hell yeah right those are great man
it's you know what's funny you know it's
funny is I'm actually doing the same
thing in my home lab this has a this has
a this moral has a point this has a
point remember that I I was saying okay
no I'm going to bring everything on Prem
on Prem on Prem and then I was like and
then I went on the bike ride and I was
like wait a second I can't have a home
lab that I have to carry around with me
I can't Port around my racks with me
anywhere I guess I could log into them
and manage him but I'm paying all this
power and energy and everything and I I
have keeping this deprecated Hardware
around it's not I need I just need to
use the cloud or something like it right
and so and then I that's why I'm
streaming from a laptop now right
because I don't need the dis frankly I
don't want to be pinned down anymore so
so I personally have gone toward more of
a thin client at home my my approach to
my own education my own home lab is Thin
Client and now I'm trying to decide okay
I need the server I need server capacity
how do I get it right well our companies
decided no you go to gcp well here's
here's the funny part so So within the
last two months I might get in trouble
this is why I don't talk about my the
company name because because it was
really funny and I'm sure somebody would
get on me for saying this but um and I'm
not not saying any names but we are
starting to get all kinds of internal
back Channel inquiries about things that
we can do that should be done in gcp and
they can't be done in gcp you know why
because they can't get a
GPU this is the best part this is crazy
this is absolutely crazy when you go to
the cloud what do you expect you expect
Cloud capacity right you expect to be
able to dial it up the whole point the
whole selling point of the cloud the
whole selling point of the cloud is you
like you're going to turn the dial
you're going to turn the dial and I need
an h100 I need an h100 for 48 hours okay
so you turn the dial all the way up and
you're run your machine learning jobs
and you pay your whatever 50k for for
your job and you can't do that Google
Cloud we we the the the the estimate I
don't know for sure I'm get in trouble
here but we were talking talking with my
peers and we're we're averaging it out
based on what we know and we're like
they we're thinking that Google probably
only makes about 20% of their GPU
capacity available to their customers
that they're selling cloud services to
so we have these big ass customers of
our product I mean of you know within
the company we have customers right
we're super big company so we have we
have customers inside the company and
they they want to buy they want to run
their their machine learning models and
they can't do it they go into gcp and if
they if they can the first problem was
them getting their these jobs are so
freaking big just getting the data to
run the job across the wire onto gcp so
that it can run without latency that's
going to [__] the bed is already a huge
deal I mean it's like a huge deal just
that one hurdle we were already having
people ask us all the time well we don't
want to do the data transfer we already
have a stff all in local stores here can
can you do it
here right and we're like well yeah
we've been doing it all along and they
said but we don't have the same SLA we
don't have a service LEL agreement is
your promise about how how how much
downtime is capacity would have and
everything like we we we're not
promising you the same thing that
they're promising you they're promising
you 5 9's uptime you know we're not
doing that we're not because we're a
small team but we're here and and and by
the way our team is exploded they've
hired like five new people in the last
year five or 10 new people because
because why because more and more people
are realizing that having that capacity
on site is necessary so they're actually
hiring people to run it we're hiring
people lots of people out of uh out of
out of uh some of the bigger uh Silicon
Valley and the bigger like government
kind of organizations are coming to our
organization because they're used to
running large deployments internally and
so and so we have you know this capacity
situation going on and then and then but
but the the real kicker is that now
these big these people who spent all
their time deploying their application
over to gcp can't get a
GPU so they can't do their jobs they
can't run they literally cannot run
their machine learning jobs because
Google just gives them a I'm sorry we
don't have any gpus available for you
this is becoming a chronic problem with
Google
cloud and it's completely opaque there's
no way for us to know Google Google's
like totally zip glip they won't tell us
what's going on they won't tell us why
our jobs aren't working they won't tell
us that they they just have to say well
we don't have capacity for that we're
over
capacity so there's some dial within
Google and you think about that for a
second before you make a decision to go
with the cloud for something like this
particularly machine learning high
performance and and most people's
machine learning jobs are business
[__] critical these are huge to the
Enterprise there all there's all the
stuff that's going especially ours if
you can't get your jobs to run you don't
make money you don't make you know
fourth quarter earnings and stuff like
that and if you trust a company like gcp
or Azure or Amazon and they say they
have GPU Computing capacity and they
don't have it and they just say sorry
looks like we didn't make SLA this time
I guess we'll have to pay the penalty oh
well so so what you get the penalties
but you don't get to do your job you
don't get to run your
model people I'm telling you right now
if if if you are thinking about if you
work for a large company if you're a CTO
or if you're in the Enterprise
architecture space at all be very very
careful about your agreements that you
have with these people that are trying
to get your business because these
things are crazy expensive as it is
they're already and that's the third
thing right so the third the third part
of this stud this third third the third
part of this of this rant is that even
when GP capacity is available and it can
be scheduled and we can get these big
massive data files over to the gcp we
have to run we have to pay through the
[__] nose for these models I mean the
amount of money that you have to pay for
that considering you know renting an
h100 I think is something somebody said
it was like 12,000 or or 2500 a day
25,000 12,000 a day no that's b100s
we're talk um I don't remember what it
is I think the b100s cost us 100 a day a
th000 a day I don't don't trust me I
don't my numbers I I I'm not involved in
that part of the business but but Nvidia
v100s and h100s uh to buy an h100 is
$25,000 um so you know fact there's you
can go on YouTube um I'm running out of
battery you can go on YouTube and you
can actually see uh there's a couple
YouTubers who were who were who were um
lucky enough to be loaned one of these
gpus in order to show it on their stream
and then they immediately had to give it
back and they had like a person in the
studio with them because they are
expensive um all my batteries are
charged yeah so anyway that's the end of
the stream today I think I made my
decision um I am going to go ahead and
Pitch I I was going to go look at kabo
for the cloud and after having this
conversation about Cloud capacity and
the hassle of was setting up the cloud
uh I'm going to go with what my gut is
telling me and my gut is telling me to
get another Tower there's $700 they're
not that much I don't need as much
capacity as I thought I needed even when
I bought that one so I could probably
get away with one that's even less than
that I'm going to buy another
refurbished dedicated machine and I'm
just going to plug it straight into my
network I'm not I'm just going to use my
home router um for my main router I'm
not going to buy a VLAN or anything like
that and then I'll chop that up and I'll
be able to access that from if it's my
own personal cloud um uh and uh
battery's charged for break yeah and
then then we don't get uh we don't we we
don't get the mobile home lab and the
trailer for the win I know and then and
then and then that way I'll be able the
thing I like about that is I'm already
using this method to VNC into my home
lab into my desktop IRL streaming
machine and so I'm just going to replace
the HP that I have there I don't I don't
know if I'm going to get another HP so
I'm going to definitely be in the market
for a tower of some kind I don't know
the capacity um but having gone through
the story about the cloud I just am very
uncomfortable with the cloud um for the
record I do use digital ocean for all my
cloud services and my DNS everything and
I I really love them their interface is
fantastic um I I do not like Amazon I've
used them a lot they're far too
complicated their interface is too
complicated people like why are you
using the guey you should be using
command line for everything on that I'm
like sometimes the web guey is is a
thing um but so if I'm if and when I'm
going to use a cloud
for some reason I was looking at kabo
because it's a much lower price point uh
for like Minecraft servers and that kind
of thing but the point the matter is is
I don't need to have public basing
server capacity I need to be able to to
chop up um a whole bunch of resources
really simply and easily and the best
way to do that is to get a tower and
chop it up so um I'm going to stick with
that recommendation from myself I'm
going to talk because I almost talked
myself into trying the cloud again and
um I just don't want to get surprised
with credit card charges and all the
stuff that happens from from the cloud
so I'm going to go ahead and and so the
next time I do a homeab stream um I may
do a little bit more of this later
tonight so we can pick one if so I'll go
ahead and publish it to YouTube um but
uh I I want to I want to finish for
today for no other reason my voice is
gone um and then we can uh but I feel
really good about that and I'm thank you
for the to the stream to my live stream
who's been chatting chiming in this
whole time time uh several of them have
recommended already towers that they
prefer and it seems like getting a tower
for a home I know that's what het Tannis
does who has much much much more
experience than I hore Tanis a big shout
out to het good good friend of mine um
uh in twitch uh and I I just bow down to
his skills when it comes to setting up
home lab kind of things and he also
prefers having a tower and chopping it
up uh specifically I think a lot of
people do that and then they'll put
proxmox on there and then proxmox kind
of helps you to chop it up pretty easily
um and thank you for the shout out
appreciate that um and that is going to
conclude the stream today um in fact
we'll go ahead and go out and raid
somebody so if you're on YouTube and
you've been sticking with this video uh
the rest of this video is just going to
be raing out me rating out to somebody
so you can end right now thank you for
joining me and we'll see is this going
to work oh my gosh it
worked how about this one yeah we can
like do all my my Mac things this is my
favorite one
though all right
everybody uh I think that's going to do
it for me today I'm going to be on the
bike join me if you want to join me for
my bike rides and we can continue to
talk while I H and pup on my bicycle uh
and we'll go we'll go give that a shot
all right so thank you YouTube all right
let's go rate
it I know I's see this one about this
one wa that's a bad sign I I think I
just flipped everybody off
right I was like that one's balloons I
think that's balloons peace peace love
and
balloons all right so
it's like all the good
stuff what is
it oh bicycle bicycle I know I want my
bicycle I want to ride my bicycle okay
wait I am going to raid somebody though
because we have a we have like a non
insignificant number of people
today people are actually here so we're
going to we're going to we're going to
go raid
someone I don't know who I'm not raiding
I'm not raiding stretchy girl
anymore
no I've
been did you
get alab bro is elab bro
on I'll rate him I'll rate
anybody
there I mean I might rate her she's the
only she was streaming to two different
streams just today I think it was
actually I think she was she was either
double streaming or she was um just
replaying a thing she wasn't even really
there you
know um I don't know who to
raid should we do Al
bro I don't mind searching I mean I can
read out
of she's pretty hot
yeah the YouTube YouTube if anybody
who's hanging on for the YouTube video
they're like what the hell is is going
on
here Pizza princess G okay let's do
that I mean why not that's somebody new
too
I
princess G here we
go twitchcon oh God definitely an IRL
stream all right bye everybody
bye bye bye bye we have to wait for the
r to go through there's a few of us
here I can't hear it though I should
probably listen to what's going on
chat what's going
on I'm supposed to be there I bought
tickets and here I am making H Lab
videos
instead I I'm getting massive fomo right
now